Guide to the Richetta Randolph Wallace Papers 1978.137
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 2. Personal Papers, 1906-1971; 6509; 1.35 Linear Feet
  - Section F. Church-Related Papers, 6612
    - Pamphlets, Other Churches, 1907-1964; 6627 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - "Church defender," by Diana Guerry Turpin (1927), 6628 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - "Emotion in religion," by William Thomas Amiger (1917), 6629 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - "Life work of the late Cora D. Shaw in the church and the community," by Bernetta Carter (1953), 6630 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - "Minutes of 14th annual session of the New England Baptist Sunday School Convention" (1907), 6631 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - "Minutes of the 18th annual meeting of the New England Sunday School Convention" (1911), 6632 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - The Mission, National Baptist Convention (1966), 6633 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Negro pulpit opinion: A monthly pamphlet of preaching, 3 issues (circa 1928), 6634 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - The pulpit: A periodical of contemporary preaching, vol. 2, no.1 (1931), 6635 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - "'Til Shiloh comes," by Marguerite and H. Gordon (1964), 6636 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - "Vignettes of persons memorialized and honored by loved ones and friends.. .," National Council of the Churches of Christ in the USA (1961), 6637 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - "St. Martin's Church: Book of the consecration" (1944), 6638 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Souvenir journal for "The Miracle," a pantomime staged by Max Reinhardt (1924), 6639 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - "The social value of death," by J. Raymond Henderson, 6642 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - The Pilot (Mt. Olivet newsletter), 1922-1926; 6640 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Programs, Flyers, and other church ephemera, 1924-1965; 6641 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Sermons delivered by Rev. S.L. Johnson (reported by R.G. Randolph), 1909; 6643 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Women's Day arrangements (1942) and other events, 1942, 1946-1947; 6644 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Series 3. James Weldon Johnson Papers, 1918-1970; 6645; 0.42 Linear Feet
  The series includes documents compiled by Richetta Randolph Wallace in connection with her work for James Weldon Johnson at the NAACP and as his personal secretary. The series includes much correspondence between the two from the 1920s in relation to business matters. The series includes a full typescript draft of Johnson's Black Manhattan, with notes, plus a galley proof of the book, as well as one folder of research conducted by Randolph for Johnson. Johnson was killed in a car accident in 1938, and the collection contains newspaper clippings about his death, plus letters to and from Carl Van Vechten, who compiled Johnson's papers into a collection currently housed at Yale University. Biographical and autobiographical material, articles, congratulatory letters, and a small collection of materials on Johnson's 1929 trip to Japan are also included.
  The series is organized in alphabetical order by subject or document type.
  - Articles by James Weldon Johnson, 1918-1928; 6646 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    "Africa in the world democracy," with Horace Meyer Kallen (1919), "Changing status of Negro labor," Address (1918), "The larger success," from The Southern Worker (1923), "Leadership and the times," Address to the NAACP (1937), "Legal aspects of the Negro problem," with Herbert Seligman (1928), "Race problem and peace" (1924), "Self-Determining Haiti" (1920), "Washington riots: An NAACP investigation" (1919), "What America owes the Negro," from Our World (1923).
  - Articles by James Weldon Johnson (oversize), 1924; 15255 (Oversize OS-23)
    "Lynching: America's national disgrace" (1924)
  - Biographical Information, 1920s-1930s; 6657 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Black Manhattan, manuscript, typescript (2 folders), circa 1930; 6658 (Box 5, Folder 2,3)
  - Black Manhattan, Galley Proof, 1930; 6659 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Black Manhattan, Research, 1930; 6660 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1930, 1933; 6661 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with Richetta Randolph Wallace, 1923-1926, 1938-1943; 6662 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Death of James Weldon Johnson, Clippings, 1938; 6663 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - God's Trombones, Congratulatory Letters and Memory Book, 1927; 6664 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Memorial and Correspondence with Carl Van Vechten, 1938-1971; 6665 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Trip to Japan, 1929; 6666 (Box 5, Folder 11)